<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://thor-f5.er.usgs.gov/ngtoc/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"[]>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</origin>
        <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
        <title>USGS National Boundary Dataset (NBD) for Georgia 20180312 State or Territory Shapefile</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
          <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>ftp://rockyftp.cr.usgs.gov/vdelivery/Datasets/Staged/GovtUnit/Shape/GOVTUNIT_Georgia_State_Shape.zip</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Geospatial data is comprised of government boundaries.</abstract>
      <purpose>It is a general purpose dataset for users who are not GIS experts. The geospatial data are from selected National Map data holdings and
        other government sources.</purpose>
      <supplinf>This data set is comprised of government boundaries.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20140203</begdate>
          <enddate>20180226</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-85.6051649999999</westbc>
        <eastbc>-80.751429</eastbc>
        <northbc>35.0013030000001</northbc>
        <southbc>30.355757</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>political and administrative boundaries</themekey>
        <themekey>legal land descriptions</themekey>
        <themekey>land use maps</themekey>
        <themekey>zoning maps</themekey>
        <themekey>cadastral surveys</themekey>
        <themekey>land ownership</themekey>
        <themekey>geographic names</themekey>
        <themekey>boundary</themekey>
        <themekey>Public Land Survey System</themekey>
        <themekey>U.S. National Grid</themekey>
        <themekey>County or Equivalent</themekey>
        <themekey>Incorporated Place</themekey>
        <themekey>Jurisdictional</themekey>
        <themekey>Minor Civil Division</themekey>
        <themekey>Native American Area</themekey>
        <themekey>PLSS First Division</themekey>
        <themekey>PLSS Special Survey</themekey>
        <themekey>PLSS Township</themekey>
        <themekey>Reserve</themekey>
        <themekey>State or Territory</themekey>
        <themekey>Unincorporated Place</themekey>
        <themekey>National Boundary Dataset (NBD)</themekey>
        <themekey>State</themekey>
        <themekey>Shapefile</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>Geographic Names Information System</placekt>
        <placekey>US</placekey>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
        <placekey>GA</placekey>
        <placekey>Georgia</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None. However, users should be aware that temporal changes may have occurred since this data set was collected and that some parts of
      this data may no longer represent actual surface conditions. Users should not use this data for critical applications without a full awareness
      of its limitations. Acknowledgment of the U.S. Geological Survey would be appreciated for products derived from these data.</useconst>
    <browse>
      <browsen>ftp://rockyftp.cr.usgs.gov/vdelivery/Datasets/Staged/GovtUnit/Shape/GOVTUNIT_Georgia_State_Shape.jpg</browsen>
      <browsed>Thumbnail JPG image</browsed>
      <browset>JPEG</browset>
    </browse>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Content is derived from USGS national geospatial databases. The data is owned and hosted by the USGS, but does not preclude using data
        sources owned and hosted by other organizations, provided that these sources have been approved by the USGS data program.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>The data is extracted and codified according to USGS standards.</logic>
    <complete>The Governmental Units Dataset is national in scope, with complete coverage of the conterminous 48 state, Hawaii, and Puerto Rico. Each
      layer is extracted from the USGS national geospatial databases.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>This product meets National Map Accuracy Standards (NMAS). NMAS horizontal accuracy requires that at least 90 percent of
          well-defined points tested are within 0.02 inch of the true position.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>Vertical accuracy is not applicable to this dataset.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>International Boundary Commission</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>U.S.-Canada National Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The boundary is a digital representation of the International boundary between the United States and Canada as per the Treaty of
              1908. It has been generated from a combination of recent surveys and datum conversions. It is intended for general mapping purposes
              only. The boundary dataset is composed of 29 segments that correspond to the original 256 boundary maps. Attributes of each segment
              define the scale in which the line in that area may be accurately depicted. It is produced for mapping purposes only and not intended to
              illustrate the boundary beyond the limits of the scale for any given segment</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.internationalboundarycommission.org/</onlink>
            <onlink>http://www.internationalboundarycommission.org/index-eng.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2006</begdate>
              <enddate>2006</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>U.S. / Canada International Boundary</srccitea>
        <srccontr>International Boundary between Canada and the United States</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin> U.S. Geological Survey, U.S. Department of Agriculture, and the Instituto Nacional de Estadistica y Geografia of Mexico. </origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>U.S.-Mexico National Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The international boundary between Mexico and the United States, defined as a joint venture between the U.S. Department of
              Agriculture (USDA) and the Instituto Nacional de Estadistica y Geografia of Mexico (INEGI), resulted in an unofficial United
              States-Mexico boundary dataset that was further enhanced by the U.S. Geological Survey's Border Environmental Health Initiative (BEHI).
              With the data frame scale set to 1:5,000 in ArcMap, the center of the Rio Grande/Rio Bravo was digitized using the NAIP 2004 Imagery. In
              areas with dense stands of salt cedar (bounding box = UL -104.714 30.038, UR -104.664 30.037, LR -104.666 29.933, LL -104.717 29.934;
              NAD83), the center of the channel was difficult, and sometimes impossible, to easily determine. To determine the location of the
              boundary, the GIS analyst compared the location of the line in the INEGI 1:250K Limite feature class with the NAIP 2004 Imagery and
              adjusted the boundary to the image, thus, the delineation of the international boundary is less certain in these areas. The remaining
              part of the border was extracted from the INEGI 1:250K Limite feature class and appended to the line feature class created along the Rio
              Grande/Rio Bravo. The U.S. Geological Survey reviewed the original USDA data against 2007 NAIP imagery and further edited 9 line
              segments in the Rio Grande areas to conform to National Map Accuracy Standards.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://borderhealth.cr.usgs.gov/projectindex.html</onlink>
            <onlink>http://extract.cr.usgs.gov/BorderHealth/Boundaries/Int_Boundary/International_Boundary_Shapefile.zip</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1972</begdate>
              <enddate>2006</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>U.S. / Mexico International Boundary</srccitea>
        <srccontr>International Boundary between Mexico and the United States</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin> U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) Forest Service - Washington Office Automated Lands Program (ALP). </origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>USDA Forest Service Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The forest service boundaries defined by the USDA Forest Service encompassing the National Forest System (NFS) lands within the
              original proclaimed National Forests, along with lands added to the NFS which have taken on the status of 'reserved from the public
              domain' under the General Exchange Act. The following area types are included: National Forest, Experimental Area, Experimental Forest,
              Experimental Range, Land Utilization Project, National Grassland, Purchase Unit, and Special Management Area. The nationwide Proclaimed
              Forest dataset was created by the USDA Forest Service, Washington Office Automated Lands Program (ALP) staff from collected source data
              created by the Regional Offices. Only maps in USDA Forest Service areas will contain USDA Forest boundaries.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2009</begdate>
              <enddate>2009</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>USDA Forest Service Boundaries</srccitea>
        <srccontr>National Forest Service Boundaries</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Office of the Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Installations and Environment, Business Enterprise Integration
              Directorate</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>U.S. Military Installations, Ranges, and Training Areas</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>This dataset depicts the authoritative boundaries of the most commonly known Department of Defense (DoD) sites, installations,
              ranges, and training areas in the United States and Territories. These sites encompass land which is federally owned or otherwise
              managed. This dataset was compiled by the Defense Installation Spatial Data Infrastructure (DISDI) Program. This dataset represents the
              baseline for georeferenced boundaries of sites selected from the 2010 Base Structure Report. The boundary locations are intended for
              planning purposes only and do not represent the legal or surveyed land parcel boundaries. This list does not necessarily represent a
              comprehensive collection of all DoD facilities, and only those in the fifty United States and US Territories were considered for
              inclusion. Maps produced at a scale of 1:50,000 or larger which otherwise comply with National Map Accuracy Standards will remain
              compliant if this data is incorporated. Although these data have been provided by the DoD components, no warranty expressed or implied
              is made regarding the utility of the data on any other system, in derived products or data alterations, nor shall the act of
              distribution constitute such warranty.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.acq.osd.mil/ie/index.shtml</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>50000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2011</begdate>
              <enddate>2011</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>U.S. Department of Defense Military Installations</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Boundary lines, installation names</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Census Bureau</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>State and Equivalent Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The Census Bureau collects boundaries from state and county governments through the Boundary and Annexation Survey, and
              publishes the results as TIGER files. The USGS uses the TIGER data without editing or alteration.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.census.gov/geo/maps-data/data/tiger.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2013</begdate>
              <enddate>2014</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>State Boundaries</srccitea>
        <srccontr>State and Equivalent Boundary</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Census Bureau</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>County and Equivalent Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The Census Bureau collects boundaries from state and county governments through the Boundary and Annexation Survey (BAS), and
              publishes the results as TIGER files. The USGS uses the TIGER data without editing or alteration for US Topo.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger/index.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2013</begdate>
              <enddate>2014</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>County Boundaries</srccitea>
        <srccontr>County and Equivalent Boundary</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Census Bureau</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>Incorporated Places Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The boundaries of most incorporated places are as of January 1, 2013, as reported through the Census Bureau's Boundary and
              Annexation Survey. Limited updates that occurred after January 1, 2013, such as newly incorporated places, are also included. The
              boundaries of all Census Designated Places (CDP) were delineated as part of the Census Bureau's Participant Statistical Areas Program
              (PSAP) for the 2010 Census. The USGS uses the TIGER data without editing or alteration.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger/index.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2013</begdate>
              <enddate>2014</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Incorporated Places Boundaries</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Incorporated Places Boundaries</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Census Bureau</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>Jurisdictional Boundary</title>
            <othercit>The 115th Congress is seated from January 2017 to 2019. The TIGER/Line shapefiles for the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and
              the Island Areas (American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the U.S. Virgin Islands) each contain a
              single record for the non-voting delegate district in these areas. The boundaries of all other congressional districts are provided to
              the Census Bureau through the Redistricting Data Program (RDP). The USGS uses the TIGER data without editing or alteration for US
              Topo.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.census.gov/geo/maps-data/data/tiger.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2016</begdate>
              <enddate>2016</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Jurisdictional Boundaries</srccitea>
        <srccontr>115th Congressional Districts Boundaries</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Census Bureau</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>Minor Civil Divisions Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The boundaries of most legal Minor Civil Divisions (MCD) are as of January 1, 2013, as reported through the Census Bureau's
              Boundary and Annexation Survey. The boundaries of all Census Designated Places (CDP)are those as reported as part of the Census Bureau's
              Participant Statistical Areas Program (PSAP) for the 2010 Census. The USGS uses the TIGER data without editing or alteration.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger/index.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2013</begdate>
              <enddate>2014</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Minor Civil Divisions Boundaries</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Minor Civil Divisions Boundaries</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Census Bureau</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>Native American Area Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The Native American Area boundaries are as of January 1, 2013 as reported through Census Bureau's Boundary and Annexation
              Survey. The USGS dataset is a combination of two Census Bureau files. It includes the American Indian/Alaska Native/Native Hawaiian
              Areas National (AIANNH) National TIGER/Line shapefile, including the following legal entities: federally recognized American Indian
              reservations and off-reservation trust land areas, state-recognized American Indian reservations, and Hawaiian home lands. Also included
              is the Alaska Native Regional Corporation (ANRC) State-based TIGER/Line shapefile containing a record of the 12 Alaska Native Regional
              Corporations used to conduct both the for-profit and non-profit affairs of Alaska Natives within a defined region of Alaska. The USGS
              uses the TIGER data without editing or alteration.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger/index.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2013</begdate>
              <enddate>2014</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Native American Area Boundaries</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Native American Area Boundaries</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>National Park Service - Land Resources Division</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>National Park Service Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>This dataset depicts National Park Service unit boundaries for display and general analysis purposes. The USGS converted areas
              of generally 3 acres or less to point features to facilitate cartographic display on the US Topo digital map product. See Source URL for
              link to complete dataset. This data set is complete but subject to continual updates to reflect boundary amendments, legislation, and
              acquisitions, and improved processing techniques. The data is being regularly updated with verified boundaries from NPS Land Resources
              Division. The data is intended for use as a tool for display and general GIS analysis purposes only. It is in no way intended for
              engineering or legal purposes. The data accuracy is checked against best available sources which may be dated. NPS assumes no liability
              for use of this data. Boundaries from the Land Resources Division have separate polygons for each type of unit. For example Denali
              National Park and Denali National Preserve are separate individual polygons.</othercit>
            <onlink>https://irma.nps.gov/App/Portal</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2002</begdate>
              <enddate>2014</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>National Park Service Boundary</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Current Administrative Boundaries of the National Park System Units</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Census Bureau</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>Unincorporated Places Boundary</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The boundaries of most unincorporated places in this shapefile are as of January 1, 2013, as reported through the Census
              Bureau's Boundary and Annexation Survey (BAS). Limited updates that occurred after January 1, 2013, such as newly unincorporated places,
              are also included. The boundaries of all Census Designated Places (CDPs) were delineated as part of the Census Bureau's Participant
              Statistical Areas Program (PSAP) for the 2010 Census. The USGS uses the TIGER data without editing or alteration.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.census.gov/geo/www/tiger/index.html</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2013</begdate>
              <enddate>2014</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Unincorporated Places Boundaries</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Unincorporated Places Boundaries</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Department of Interior, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>US Fish and Wildlife Service</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>This data set depicts simplified boundaries of lands administered by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service including National
              Wildlife Refuges, National Fish Hatcheries, FWS administrative sites, and other conservation areas. The Alaska National Wildlife Refuge
              Boundaries data set depicts the legislative boundary of the 16 National Wildlife Refuges in Alaska at a source scale of 1:63,360. The
              dataset was created by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Region 7, Division of Realty and Natural Resources. The USGS substituted the
              Alaska National Wildlife Refuge boundaries for the USFWS Simplified Wildlife Refuge Boundaries in Alaska for cartographic purposes. The
              USFWS Simplified Wildlife Refuge Boundaries are simplified from the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service Real Estate Interest data layer
              containing polygons representing tracts of land (parcels) in which the Service has a property or management interest. These interests
              include full land ownership, secondary interests in property primarily managed and reported by other federal agencies, leased property,
              property managed by agreement with other parties, and, within National Wildlife Refuges, property governed by conservation easements. A
              conservation easement is a permanent, legally enforceable land preservation agreement between a landowner and a government agency that
              restricts real estate, commercial and industrial development of the land, which remains private property. Inholdings of private property
              within Refuge areas not covered by conservation easements are excluded from these boundaries. The Hawaiian Islands National Wildlife
              Refuge and Waterfowl production area easements acquired through the small wetlands program have been omitted. Interior boundaries
              between parcels were dissolved to produce a single set of simplified external boundaries for each feature. These are resource grade
              mapping representations of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service boundaries. For legal descriptions of the land represented here contact
              the USFWS Realty Office. This map layer was compiled by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. The Alaska National Wildlife Refuges dataset
              was derived from the following digital sources and legal documents: 1) Federal Register, Vol. 48, No. 38 Thursday, February 24, 1983
              Notices Pages 7890-8029. 2) USGS 1:250,000 scale Alaska Boundary Series maps entitled: Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act
              December 2, 1980 P.L. 96-487 3) Various legal documents such as survey plats, legal metes and bounds descriptions, Deeds, and Titles. 4)
              USGS 1:63,360 scale revised hydrography Digital Line Graphs depicting ground conditions from 1955 to 1986. Although these Fish and
              Wildlife boundaries represent lands administered by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, not all areas are open to the public. Some
              fragile habitats need to be protected from human traffic, some management areas are closed, and the terms of some conservation easements
              preclude public access. The public is urged to contact specific Refuges or other conservation areas before visiting.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://www.fws.gov/GIS/data/CadastralDB/FWS_Simplified_Boundaries.zip</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>1950</begdate>
              <enddate>2014</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service Boundary</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Boundary polygons and names</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Dept. of Interior, Bureau of Land Management, Division of Support Services, Branch of Information Resource
              Management</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>Public Land Survey System</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>The PLSS information is for general reference purposes only, and should not be used to determine legal boundaries or land
              ownership. The Bureau of Land Management (BLM) is the authoritative source for PLSS information at the federal level, and the US Topo
              representation is derived from BLM GIS data files called Cadastral National Spatial Data Infrastructure or CadNSDI. The management of
              these data is not completely uniform throughout the country. Although this metadata record is included with all maps, PLSS is currently
              shown on US Topo Maps for only a few states. PLSS will be added to US Topo maps in more states in coming years as BLM authorized CadNSDI
              format is made available. The three layers USGS stores from PLSS are the Township, First Division and Special Surveys. Metadata for BLM
              PLSS data is at http://www.geocommunicator.gov/GeoComm/metadata/index.htm#PLSS, though this URL may change in the near future. Alternate
              sources of PLSS data will continued to be served mainly in western states where BLM is the data steward or the data is from a trusted
              source. Notes on individual states follow,----Alaska PLSS consists of protracted (computed, not surveyed) data only. For more
              information see http://sdms.ak.blm.gov/sdms/data_protracted_grid_gis.html----Ohio was the original PLSS state in the early 1800s, and
              the land network there is unusually complex. The source data include four first-division parcel types. These are all shown on US Topo
              maps, and are labeled according to BLM's attribution, with a leading letter followed by either a number or more letters. The meanings of
              the leading letters are S=Section, F=Fractional Section, L=Lot, Q=Quarter Township.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://sdms.ak.blm.gov/sdms/data_protracted_grid_gis.html</onlink>
            <onlink>http://www.geocommunicator.gov/GeoComm/lsis_home/home/index.htm</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2012</begdate>
              <enddate>2012</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Public Land Survey System - BLM</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Townships and ranges, sections</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Department of Veterans Affairs, National Cemetery Administration and U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
            <pubdate>20180312</pubdate>
            <title>NCA National Cemeteries</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <othercit>This dataset represents boundaries of National cemeteries administered by the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs, National
              Cemetery Administration. This layer may also contain a small number of boundaries for those managed by the Department of the Army. This
              data is subject to change as other national cemetery areas are authorized. This dataset is intended for general mapping and reference
              purposes only.</othercit>
            <onlink>http://nationalmap.gov/boundaries.html/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>2013</begdate>
              <enddate>2014</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>National Cemetery Boundary</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Name, general location information from NCA, Boundaries from parcel and other mapping datasets.</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The data for this product are created as follows. All geospatial content is taken from national geospatial databases under the
          stewardship of USGS data programs. The vector data are processed using ESRI ArcGIS software and exported.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20180312</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>0.00001</latres>
        <longres>0.00001</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.2572221</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>1400 Independence Road</address>
          <city>Rolla</city>
          <state>MO</state>
          <postal>65401</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Box 25046 Denver Federal Center</address>
          <city>Lakewood</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80225</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>http://www.usgs.gov/ask/</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM</hours>
        <cntinst>Metadata information can also be obtained through online services using The National Map Viewer, at http://nationalmap.usgs.gov or
          EarthExplorer, at http://earthexplorer.usgs.gov or Ask USGS at http://www.usgs.gov/ask.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>No liability for content or accuracy is presumed by USGS for data.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>FileGDB</formname>
          <formvern>10.1</formvern>
          <formcont>Spatial objects with unique identifiers and coordinate data.</formcont>
          <filedec>No compression applied</filedec>
          <transize>40440394</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>ftp://rockyftp.cr.usgs.gov/vdelivery/Datasets/Staged/GovtUnit/Shape/GOVTUNIT_Georgia_State_Shape.zip</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>None</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20180312</metd>
    <metrd>20180312</metrd>
    <metfrd>20190312</metfrd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>1400 Independence Road</address>
          <city>Rolla</city>
          <state>MO</state>
          <postal>65401</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Box 25046 Denver Federal Center</address>
          <city>Lakewood</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80225</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-ASK-USGS (1-888-275-8747)</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>http://www.usgs.gov/ask/</cntemail>
        <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM</hours>
        <cntinst>Metadata information can also be obtained through online services using The National Map Viewer, at http://nationalmap.usgs.gov or
          EarthExplorer, at http://earthexplorer.usgs.gov or Ask USGS at http://www.usgs.gov/ask.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>